# Michael Curran

# Developer

Passionate Computer Science student and web developer. Using HTML5 and CSS and JS to build all aspects of web applications. I pride myself on understanding and delivering on client's expectations through excellent communication and rational problem solving. My experience has taught me that even the most daunting tasks a developer can face can be overcome by thorough research, strategic planning and a thoughtful approach.

#### **Work Experience**

## **Volunteer Developer** at Spicy Green Book

October 2020 - Present

Currently working with a team to overhaul an existing web application that assists users in finding Black owned businesses.

- Identifying bugs and implementing fixes
- Creating wireframes and graphics that adhere to the client's brand using Figma and Adobe Illustrator.

### Web Developer at Freelance

March 2018 - Present

Currently advising and developing all aspects of client applications from web and graphic design to server-side back end logic.

- Reduced bounce rates by up to 17% by simplifying UI/UX Design.
- Creating inspired and unique graphic designs and logos while adhering to the client's brand using Adobe Illustrator and Adobe Photoshop
- Produced project deliverables 98% on time with minimal necessary rework

# Kitchen Manager at Back East Bar & Grill

October 2014 - October 2019

Commended for having a great management style and excellent communication skills.

- Trained and hired new staff increasing employee retention significantly
- Slashed labor costs by 8% by formulating a new scheduling system

#### **Recent Personal Projects**

# **Brawl Buddy** created on MERN stack

Displays user statistics fetched from the official Brawlhalla API. Includes a ranked leaderboard, individual user statistics plus stat trends for highly ranked users, and a stream tool to view stats per session. https://brawl-buddy.herokuapp.com

#### **Contact Details**

**Phone**: 386-690-0749

**Email**: Mcurran1722@gmail.com **Location**: Colorado Springs, CO

Github:

https://Github.com/micurran

Codepen:

https://codepen.com/micurran

Portfolio:

https://michaelcurran.vercel.app

#### **Expertise**

5 years
5 years
3 years
2 years
1 year

#### Certifications

CIW Site Development Associate

2019 - Present

#### Education

Computer Science Western Governors University 2019 - Present

Computer Programming and Analysis Daytona State College 2011 - 2013